<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anoushka</title>
    <link>https://anoushkajoglekar.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Anoushka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://anoushkajoglekar.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>_Nature Communications, 2021_</title>
      <link>https://anoushkajoglekar.com/publications/natcomms_2021.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anoushkajoglekar.com/publications/natcomms_2021.html</guid>
      <description>A spatially resolved brain region- and cell type-specific isoform atlas of the postnatal mouse brain Abstract:
Splicing varies across brain regions, but the single-cell resolution of regional variation is unclear. We present a single-cell investigation of differential isoform expression (DIE) between brain regions using single-cell long-read sequencing in mouse hippocampus and prefrontal cortex in 45 cell types at postnatal day 7 (www.isoformAtlas.com). Isoform tests for DIE show better performance than exon tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>_Nature Biotechnology, 2022_</title>
      <link>https://anoushkajoglekar.com/publications/naturebiotech_2022.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anoushkajoglekar.com/publications/naturebiotech_2022.html</guid>
      <description>Single-nuclei isoform RNA sequencing unlocks barcoded exon connectivity in frozen brain tissue Abstract:
Single-nuclei RNA sequencing characterizes cell types at the gene level. However, compared to single-cell approaches, many single-nuclei cDNAs are purely intronic, lack barcodes and hinder the study of isoforms. Here we present single-nuclei isoform RNA sequencing (SnISOr-Seq). Using microfluidics, PCR-based artifact removal, target enrichment and long-read sequencing, SnISOr-Seq increased barcoded, exon-spanning long reads 7.5-fold compared to naive long-read single-nuclei sequencing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
